ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
木浅薰
小酸奶!
翻译
吃冰棒
电脑团
时间轴
大葱ALX  念念  今
电脑狂人
第四季
第一集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
最新版本  免费试用50小时
谭雅·里斯
工商管理硕士
艺术学学士
千禧
放弃游戏是否
新年快乐
Happy New Year.
东京怎么样
How's Tokyo?
很好
Good.
很冷
Cold.
很好  很好...
Good. Good. Well, uh...
是她吗
Is that her?
我们为浏览器制定了几项初步计划
We got some first steps for the browser
想跟你说说  这样等你回来
that we want to walk you through so we can, uh, you know,
我们就能直接开始开展工作
hit the ground running when you get back to town.
戈登  我得远程参与这个项目了
Gordon, I'm gonna be working on this project remotely.
我想和乔谈谈
I-I need to talk to Joe.
就我们俩
Just me.
好吧
Yeah. Okay.
她想和你说
Wants to talk to you.
喂
Hello?
你好吗
How you doing?
我不明白
I don't understand.
我和汤姆说了发生的事
I told Tom what happened.
他和我  我们都同意
And he and I, uh, we both agreed
我最好
that it would be best
还是待在这里远程
if I worked on the browser remotely --
参与浏览器工作
from here.
那里现在是几点
What time is it there?
他们比我们快17个小时
They're 17 hours ahead,
所以不管这里是什么时间...
so whatever time it is here...
她不需要在电话那头
Look, she doesn't need to be on the phone
用于在互联网上查询资料
我们也能上传到地鼠for us to upload it to Gopher.
是她写的  她必须得在
She wrote it. She needs to be available.
伙计们  我得...
Guys, I need -- I need --
别锤了
Stop hammering!
拜托
Please!
你知道那里现在是半夜
You know it's midnight there.
如果这是她指定的时间
This is the time she specified.
也许哥斯拉又在大战魔斯拉了
Maybe Godzilla's fighting Mothra again.
我们过20分钟再联络她
We're gonna try her again in 20 minutes.
伙计们
Guys!
伙计们  伙计们  拜托
Guys, guys, please!
行了
All right?
一大清早的
It's too early in the morning for this.
那是因为根本没有人在下载
That is because nobody is downloading it at all.
不  你说得对  原谅我
No, you're right. Forgive me.
上一季度有69人下载了  是不是好一点
69 downloads last quarter. Is that better?
都一年了  我们根本没打开市场
A year and we are barely a ripple in the pond.
当然跟那些漏洞有关
Of course it has to do with the bugs.
我已经在尽快查了
I'm tracking them as fast as I can,
但你总要那么久...
but you take forever to --
好吧
Okay.
好吧  好
Okay, fine.
没问题
That would be fine.
-卡梅伦怎么样  -从来没时间
- How's Cameron? - Never available.
就算我们想办法让她接了电话
Or if we do somehow manage to get her on the phone,
她要么很忙  要么很冲  要么
she's busy or defensive or --
只有69个下载
Stuck at 69 downloads.
乔  我们在楼上
Look, Joe, we're building
搭建网络服务提供商核心业务
the core ISP business upstairs by the day,
所以我们不需要浏览器一夜之间大获成功
which means we don't need overnight success with the web browser.
但你为什么老是要这样和她纠缠呢
But why do you keep putting yourself through this with her?
这个项目很重要
This work is important.
我不是问这个
That's not what I asked.
我会确保修复好那些漏洞
I'll make sure those bugs get fixed.
谢普  你和卡梅伦聊过吗
Shep, have you talked to Cameron?
戈登  这是美国在线的麦克·豪斯曼
Gordon, this is Mike Houseman from America Online.
-很高兴认识你  戈登  -我也是
- Great to meet you, Gordon. - Yeah, likewise.
我想和你谈谈收购你们的用户群
Yeah, I want to talk about acquiring your user base.
美国在线这么害怕开放网络吗
Is AOL really that afraid of the open Internet?
不然等我们向西扩张就会完全挤垮你们
Well, it's either that or we crush you when we expand west.
那我告诉你  麦克
Well, let me tell you something, Mike --
我得马上给你看点东西
I need to show you something right now.
麦克  这是乔·麦克米伦
Mike, this is Joe MacMillan.
他是我们的网络服务部
He's our Web Services division.
真厉害  你研究网络
Impressive. You're into the Web.
那是前景所在
It's where everything's headed.
戈登
Gordon.
失陪一下
Excuse us.
名字是马赛克
It's called Mosaic.
好吧  又有浏览器下场抢食了
All right, so there's another browser in the game.
还有奈克萨斯  维奥拉  迈达斯
We still got Nexus, Viola, Midas...
均是早期浏览器
别忘了唐娜的杰作  千禧浏览器
Don't forget Millennium, thanks to Donna.
她和我们一样有权开发这个点子
Who's got just as much of a right to this idea as we do.
但是这个不一样
But those aren't this.
内嵌图片  网络论坛支持
Inline images, Web forums support,
全平台通用
available on every platform.
要是卡梅伦没有五个月不见人影
If Cameron hadn't been radio silent for five months,
要是她能及时修复漏洞  帮我们迭代
if she had fixed the bugs, helped us iterate...
输了我不在乎
I don't mind losing,
但我们连竞争的机会都没有
but we're not even gonna get a chance to compete.
卡梅伦哪去了
Where the hell is Cameron?
现在我们做自己的芯片吧
Now we do our own chip.
这边
Over here.
你没事吧
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
我没事
Fine.
她肯定是在做新游戏
I bet it was her new game.
她肯定只是忙得太投入
I'm sure she just got wrapped up in it,
把我们都给忘了
forgot all about us.
如果我们取消应用限制呢
What if we uncapped usage?
让所有用户自由使用
You know, unlimited access for every customer...
取消按小时计费
you know, no more hourly rates,
只设置一个月费
just a, you know, flat monthly fee?
好主意  高明
That's a good idea, smart.
不是我抓住这事不放
Look, I don't mean to harp on it,
但我就是觉得她欠我们一个最终版本
but what galls me is that she still owes us a final version.
我们本有先发优势
We had a first-mover advantage.
结果现在马赛克成了网络的大门
Now Mosaic is the front door to the Web.
是啊  我听说他们头六个月
Yeah, I heard they had a million downloads
就有一百万下载量
in the first six months.
这个数字肯定注水了
Those numbers have to be inflated.
与此同时
Meanwhile,
北极星的下载量高达惊人的431
Loadstar stands at a whopping 431.
也许没什么要紧
Well, maybe that's okay.
但我们明明能大败马赛克
But we can build a Mosaic-killer.
但她就是不肯做
She couldn't do it.
那我们就找个能做的
We'll find someone who can.
乔  你非得每次都是对的吗
Joe, how many times do you have to be right?
也许我们心怀感激就够了
Maybe we should just be grateful or something.
你看这种技术
I mean, this is technology
是我们当初在车库做梦都想不到的
that we could only have dreamed of back in that garage.
你该把奥齐也叫来
You should've brought Ozzie.
我不介意的
I wouldn't have minded.
怎么了
What?
没什么
Nothing.
我们三个星期前分手了
We broke up three weeks ago.
天啊
Oh, man.
戈登
Hey, Gordon...
40岁生日快乐
happy 40th.
干杯
Cheers.
再试试那条走廊
Try the corridor again.
我们刚刚走过了
We were just there,
只找到了根破拐杖似的东西
and all we found was this rusty walking-stick thing.
能装备吗
Can you equip it?
"手杖在你手中化作尘埃"
"The stick particulates in your hand"?
太好了
Cool.
哥们  什么鬼
Dude, what?
感觉像做作业
This feels like homework.
说真的  我看着都快无聊死了
Seriously, I'm getting cold just watching this.
太好了  又一个谜题
Good... another puzzle.
还好我们十多分钟连个人影都没看见
Good thing we haven't seen anybody in like 10 minutes.
甚至都不能打怪
You can't even kill anything.
该死
Shoot.
好吧
Okay.
等等  什么鬼  我们又回到起点了
Wait. What the hell? We're back at the beginning?
这什么破玩意
This is bullshit.
你是谁
Who are you?
你们现在最喜欢的电子游戏是什么
What's your favorite video game right now?
-《真人快打》  -是啊  《真人快打》
- Mortal Kombat. - Yeah, Mortal Kombat.
我更喜欢《街霸2》
I prefer Street Fighter II.
控制更流畅  画面效果更华丽
for the superior controls and graphics.
好吧  多谢你们的参与
Okay. Thank you, guys, for coming in.
这是你们的炸鸡代金券
Here's your Pioneer Chicken gift certificates.
感谢你们的反馈
We appreciate your feedback.
几位  他们不是我们的目标用户
Guys, this is not our target demographic.
我们要争取学习成绩更好的
We need to be going after higher GPAs,
喜欢浸入式魔幻和科幻作品的消费者
readers with immersive fantasy and sci-fi interests.
这个游戏不是拿来玩的  而是拿来体验的
This isn't a game you play. It's a game you live.
多少个网站了
How many websites now?
561个
561.
而且我又给你找到个新的
And I found a new one for you.
如果是那个能把你的名字翻成夏威夷语的
Look, if this is the one that translates your name into Hawaiian,
-我已经试过了  -结果如何
- I already did it. - And?
可乐可呐
Kolekona.
再看看这个
Look at this one.
这是个  咖啡壶
It's a, uh... It's a coffee pot.
这是一个位于剑桥大学的咖啡壶
That is a coffee pot at he University of Cambridge,
在五千英里之外
5,000 miles away.
这不是张图片  这是直播视频
That's not a picture. That's a live video feed.
看上去还真生动啊
Well, it looks really alive.
真是  太厉害了
It's...fascinating.
听着
Listen.
乔  我下来其实是想
Joe, I actually came down here
和你说件事情
to chat with you about something.
说吧
Shoot.
我在想你要不要搬去楼上工作
Well, I was wondering if you'd consider moving upstairs.
为什么
Why?
网络服务部
Well, the Web Services division
没有像预期的那样取得什么进展
hasn't originally grown the way we thought it would,
而且我们需要地方放服务器
and, you know, we could really use the server space.
现在浏览器项目又完蛋了
And... And now that the browser's dead...
完蛋了  我们可能是滞后了一点
Dead? We might have stalled a little bit,
但那是因为我们才刚刚开始
but that's because we're just getting started.
我不上楼
I'm not moving upstairs.
就算要搬  也是你搬下来
If anything, you're moving down here.
乔  你听我说  你在下面待了快三年了
Listen, Joe, you've been down here for almost three years,
还是只有你一个人  一张人体工学椅子
and it's still just you, an ergonomic chair,
还有500张便贴
and 500 Post-its.
你听好  我再说一遍
Listen. I'll say it again.
你做到了  你和莱恩看得很准
You did it. You and Ryan called it.
你说过网络将会成为下一个重要的公共服务
You said the Internet would be the next great public utility.
你猜怎么着  我们已经走到了这一步
Well, guess what? We're here.
我们做到了  我们就像爱迪生
We did it. We are Thomas Edison.
我们创立了网络的电力公司
We built the power company.
所以你为什么不搬到楼上来
So why don't you come upstairs
和我一起经营这个电力公司呢
and run the power company with me?
戈登  没人会记住电力公司的名字
Gordon, nobody remembers the power company.
和我这个月的《大众机械》一起寄来的
Came free in the mail with my Popular Mechanics this month.
美国在线正在地毯式轰炸
AOL is carpet-bombing.
他们准备杀进我们的领域
They're going after our entire territory.
他们正在打击计算机服务和天才两家
They're trying to take down CompuServe and Prodigy,
但是我们很可能会被连带摧毁
but we could get caught in the crossfire.
我只是想说  如果我们要打仗
All I'm saying is, if we're about to go to war,
你能上前线就最好不过了
it'd be nice to have you in the fight.
天啊  都能看视频了
Jesus. It has video now.
他妈...
Mother...
不行  亚伯  你今天上午就得全面执行升级
No, Abe, you needed to fully implement the updates this morning!
你试试抱着个
You try reformatting HTML
又哭又闹的6个月孩子修改网页
with a screaming 6-month-old in your arm.
真是会赶巧啊你
Oh, that's just great timing, isn't it?
-是啊  -那好
- Oh, yeah, it is. - Yeah. Okay, good.
她马上就到
She'll be right with you.
谢谢
Thank you.
胡萝卜  西柚  外加一点姜
Carrot, grapefruit, little bit of ginger.
微软的主页宣布没有得到
Microsoft didn't get the bump they wanted
预期的效应
from the Home announcement.
我知道  才0.5%
I know. Two hundredths of a point.
但Windows还是白宫的官方系统
Well, Windows is still the official O.S. of the White House.
早上好
Good morning.
首先  非常感谢你今早让我们来
First off, thanks for calling us in this morning.
相信我  要是你没有联系我们
Believe me, if you hadn't had reached out,
我们也...
we would've --
我们肯定也会想办法来见你
You know, we would've been bothering you to get in here
因为我们很兴奋
because we are just so darn excited
我们打算采取一些能超越马赛克的措施
about some of these steps we're taking to surpass Mosaic.
等我们执行完毕
By the time we are done fully implementing,
马赛克就什么都不是了
it'll be like, "Mosaic? What's Mosaic?"
所以  来跟你汇报一下进度
So, just to catch you up,
千禧现在支持...
Millennium now supports...
好的
Right.
内嵌图像了
inline images.
下面还添加了停止按钮
Yeah, we got a stop button right there
停止网页加载  看
to halt web-page loads. See?
很快我们的推荐列表就要上线了
And, uh, we should have our very own "Hotlists" soon.
视频呢
Video?
是的  当然
Yes. Yes, of course.
我们正在努力  用不了几天了
We are hard at work on that. Matter of days.
我们还提前展开了品牌推广
We've also been proactive with our branding efforts --
把我们的名声传出去
you know, getting our name out there.
格雷格  鼠标垫  谢谢
Greg, the mouse pads, please.
为了广而告之
You know, to spread the word,
我们的下载量  虽然还没赶上马赛克
and, um, our download numbers, while not Mosaic's,
但是已经开始挤掉北极星了  所以...
are really starting to edge out Loadstar, so...
但我们不能只想着追赶马赛克  对吗
But we don't want to be just chasing Mosaic, do we?
你们的天分远不止于此
You guys are too talented for that.
你们要追求自己的想法
You need to be pursuing your own vision,
不能总模仿别人  对吧
not aping somebody else's, right?
再同意不过了  没错
We couldn't agree more. Yes.
很好
Wonderful.
那就这样了
Then we are all set.
我之前真的很支持你们的
I was really rooting for you guys.
谢谢  唐娜  我们很感激
Thanks, Donna. We really appreciate it.
我们是不是失去了资助
Did we just get defunded?
-别碰我  -是你问我的
- Get your hands off me. - You asked.
我说了别碰我  亚伯
I said don't touch me, Abe!
真是
Jesus!
好
All right!
好吧
All right.
瞧瞧谁来了
Look who it is.
公司的邀请名单上有我
I was on the company invite list.
所以你还是能收到邮件的
So you do get e-mails.
-看到马赛克了吗  -看到马赛克了
- Have you seen Mosaic? - I saw Mosaic.
都五个月没你的音讯了
I haven't heard from you in five months.
你就这么突然出现了
Now you're just here.
说实话  我都不知道你回国了
Honestly, I didn't even know you were in the country.
我很抱歉  我应该...
Yeah, I'm sorry. I should've --
我以为能有时间和你谈谈的
You know, I-I thought I was gonna find time to talk to you.
我没想到派对会这么...
I didn't know the party was gonna be so --
听着  没事的
Look, look, look. Don't worry about it.
说实话  我都没那么生气
To be honest with you, I'm not even that mad.
不过乔会杀了你的
Joe's gonna kill you.
他在吗
Is he here?
乔·麦克米伦会来派对
Joe MacMillan at a party?
你真是离开太久了
You've been out of the loop for a while.
来抱抱
Well, come on!
你怎么来这里了
Hey, what the heck are you doing here?
天哪  看看
My God! Look!
我是在  推广我的新游戏
I'm -- I'm doing some, um, promotion for my new game.
那个《朝圣者》啊  我看到了
Yeah, The Pilgrim, sure. I've seen it.
看上去挺吓人
Ooh, looks spooky.
对了  约翰非常喜欢那个航海罗盘
By the way, John absolutely loved that sailing compass.
是啊  我把它安在防水墙上了
Sure. I got it mounted right on the bulkhead.
我们得抽点时间过去
You know, we got to get over there
见见他们  越快越好
and see these guys some time. Soon?
只等黛安想到要怎么能报销
Once Diane figures out how to make it business write-off.
约翰  谢谢了
Gee, John, thanks.
我开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
你们什么时候来都欢迎
Oh, I mean, you guys are welcome whenever you want.
我刚看到琼妮  去打个招呼
I just saw Joanie, so I'm gonna go say hi.
好的  很高兴见到你
Okay. Good to see you.
你什么时候带我去那艘船上
When are you gonna take me out on that boat?
我们很快就去  船长
Oh, we'll get out there soon, Cap'n.
我去洗洗
I'm gonna go get cleaned up.
好的  你是该洗洗
Okay. You need it.
待会儿见
See you guys in a little bit.
好
Okay.
从这场面来看
By the looks of all this,
卡奈特一年得挣了五六千万吧
CalNect pulls down, what, 50, 60 mil a year?
我觉得是六千
I'll say it's 60.
进入亚利桑那后得有七千五了
Well, hell, 75 now that they're down in Arizona.
但已经有25家网络服务提供商  并且还在增多
Still, 25 ISP competitors in the landscape and growing,
卡奈特还不是CIX成员
and CalNect isn't a member of the C.I.X.
商业互联网交换  现代互联网的重要雏形之一
并且近期内也不会加入
and won't be anytime soon.
也对
Well, yeah.
戈登看家的本领还是不错的
Gordon's pretty good at watching his henhouse.
我觉得不必担心
I wouldn't worry.
约翰  我只是说  美国在线要进来的话
John, all I'm saying is that with AOL coming to town,
你不觉得这一切看上去有点过于乐观了吗
all of this seems overly optimistic, don't you think?
卡梅伦
Cameron?
天哪  天哪
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
-真不敢相信你来了  -好吧
- I can't believe you're here! - Okay.
天哪  大家听好
Oh, my God! Guys, listen.
这是卡梅伦  就是那个卡梅伦·豪伊
This is Cameron. Like -- like, the Cameron Howe.
-是我  -不赖嘛
- Yes. - Nice, dude.
她发明了《太空摩托》
She invented Space Bike.
另一个叫什么来着
What's the other one called?
《朝圣者》
Pilgrim.
对
Right.
酷毙了
That is so cool.
你想玩《真人快打》吗
Do you wanna play Mortal Kombat?
来吧
Yeah.
不了  你们继续
No. You guys go ahead.
海莉
Haley?
好久不见了[日语]
O hisashiburi desu ne.
厉害
Impressive.
我一直在跟着你寄来的光盘练习
I've been, you know, practicing off those CDs you sent.
很好  但是语言是学无止境的
Yes. Well, gengo o hitotsu wa kesshite tarinai.
你是个很棒的胡萝卜[日语]
Anata wa subarashi ninjindesu.
不对吗
No?
-不对  -怎么了
- No. - No, what?
你刚才说我是个很棒的胡萝卜
You said I was an awesome carrot.
你不用担心
You don't have to worry.
我妈不在
My mom's not here.
你来啦
Hey, man.
见到你真好
Good to see ya.
我以为你来不了的
I didn't think you'd make it.
很高兴我还能让你意外啊
Glad to know I can still surprise you.
没有礼物吗
So, um, no present?
我还真给你带了点东西
Actually, I did get you something.
我开玩笑呢
I was kidding.
电影院的前台有一整箱
A whole box of them at the front counter at Blockbuster.
老天  美国在线现在真是无处不在
Jesus. AOL's everywhere now.
我会和你并肩作战
I'm, uh -- I'm in this fight with you.
但我想要谢普的办公室  那里阳光最好
But I want Shep's office. It gets the most sunlight.
行
Done.
卡梅伦来了
Cameron's here.
好  我记下了你的网址
Okay, so I've got http//cad.ucla/edu/repository/bonsai/html.
对  就是这个
Yep. That's it.
你也是个盆栽爱好者吗
You're a fellow bonsai enthusiast, I take it?
不是
No.
但我会去看你的网站的
But I'm gonna check out your website.
好吧
Okay.
我听说你都不参加派对了
I heard you didn't come to parties anymore.
今天是戈登的生日
It's Gordon's birthday.
汤姆还好吗
How's Tom?
汤姆挺好的
Tom is good.
他...
He, um...
他刚升职为
He just got promoted
世嘉公司的开发部主管  所以...
to head of development at Sega, so...
挺好
That's great.
你生我的气了
You're mad at me.
换成是你你不会吗
Wouldn't you be?
是啊
Yeah.
我要走了
I got to go.
谢谢你们过来
Thank you all for coming!
能给我来杯威士忌吗
Can I have a whiskey?
我残忍吗
Am I cruel?
当然不了
Of course not.
为什么这么问
Why would you ask that?
好了
All right.
现在几点了
What time is it?
大中午了  太阳晒屁股了
Crack of noon. Rise and shine.
天呐  你真坏
Oh, God. You're a monster.
如果你需要的话皮特可以送你回家
Pete can give you a ride home if you need one.
谁是皮特
Who's Pete?
我的司机  你会喜欢他的
My driver. You'll love him.
他以前是个城市税务规划师
He used to be a city tax planner
喜欢听有声书
and loves books on tape.
车里暗吗
Is it dark in the car?
我能在这里开空调睡觉吗
Can I sleep in there with the A.C. On?
当然
Of course.
只要你不介意罗伯特·陆德伦的
As long as you're all right with the dulcet tones
恐怖电影的美妙声音
of Robert Ludlum thrillers.
甜甜圈平原3太难了
Man, Donut Plains 3 is impossible.
战斗模式啊
Battle mode?
好  来吧
Yeah, you're on.
好吧
All right.
天啊
Oh, Jesus.
来  你得选个人
All right, you got to pick a guy.
什么  你选蛤蟆  不是吧
What, Toad? Really?
他拐弯最厉害
He corners the best.
有意思
Interesting.
好吧  这很有可能会害我吐出来
Okay, there's a decent chance this is gonna make me barf.
你今早和琼妮的情况一样
You and Joanie are in the same boat this morning.
你可以扔香蕉皮吗
You can throw banana peels?
你怎么这么会玩这个
How'd you get so good at this?
我大概一年半前
I got my hands on a prototype cartridge
就拿到卡带原型机了
about a year and a half ago.
你还真把西南部传统带到这儿来了
Man, you really brought the Southwest in here,
不是吗  戈登
didn't you, Gordon?
少来
Easy.
你还要在城里待多久
How much longer are you in town for?
不知道
I don't know.
但如果你想看到最疯狂的场面
But if you want to see the craziest thing,
就该去看看为我新游戏做测试的焦点小组
you should swing by the focus-group testing for my new game.
就跟《灵魂大搜索》里一样
It's like "Altered States"
但不是服了迷药而是在做市场调研
but with market research instead of LSD.
那这游戏最好很好玩
That damn game better be good.
不是吧  我刚得了一个红贝壳
Of course, right when I get a red shell.
给你
Here.
你看看好不好玩
You tell me if it's good.
《朝圣者》
"Pilgrim."
我很高兴你能这么成功  戈登
I'm glad you're doing so well, Gordon.
谢谢
Thanks.
是啊
Yeah.
我干得真的真的很好
I'm doing really, really great.
昨晚  我都成了人体画笔了
I mean, last night, I got to be a human paintbrush.
我看见了
I saw that.
卡奈特很有竞争力
You know, CalNect is... it's kicking ass.
我很遗憾只有北极星没成
Well, I'm sorry that Loadstar has to be the exception.
-我  -得了
- I... - Come on.
我说实话
You know, if I'm being totally honest,
随着时间推移  浏览器对于我
as time wore on, the browser just became
更多是个附带项目
more of a side project for me.
它一直是乔的宝贝
It's always been Joe's baby.
乔
Joe.
我昨晚见到他了
I saw him last night.
然后呢
And?
戈登  不是很愉快
Oh, Gordon, it didn't go that well.
那样或许也好
Well, that's probably for the best.
对于谁
For who?
对于他
For him.
该死
Oh, shit!
怎么了
What?
孩子们还没走呢
The girls haven't left yet.
海莉  琼妮  来啊  走了
Haley, Joanie! Come on! Let's go!
戈登
Gordon?
不  她从不进来的  别担心
No, she never comes in. Don't worry.
好吧  那周三见了
All right, well, um, I'll see you Wednesday.
我也爱你
Love you, too.
琼妮  快走
Joanie, let's go!
戈登
Gordon?
你看到马赛克了吗
Uh, have you seen Mosaic?
看到了
Yes.
我很意外居然不是你的
I was surprised it wasn't you.
她可能...
She may have gotten into the...
爸爸
Dad.
快走
Get out here.
多谢
Thanks for this.
嗯
Yeah.
不客气
Anytime.
她很少进来的
She rarely comes in.
不出所料  固定费率和检修消耗
As expected, the flat fee and unkept usage
起初拉低了总体收入
dinged the overall revenue initially,
但现在我们交易大了
but now we're in the volume business.
用户群在不断扩大
The user base just keeps going up.
那这就不是回弹  是可持续增长
Then this isn't a rebound. It's sustained growth.
那很好
That's good.
问题是  带宽不够用了
Only problem is the pipe's getting tight.
数据量那么大  我们开始出现堵塞了
We're starting to clog a little bit with all that data.
世通[电信企业]听说我们业绩多好
MCI hears how well we're doing,
会想重新就私下交易谈判
they're gonna want to renegotiate the sweetheart deal
然后给我们更多他们双绞线网络的带宽
before they give us more bandwidth on their twisted pair network.
我们可以表现出犹豫  去跟太平洋贝尔联络
We could balk and try PacBell,
但说到底
but at the end of the day,
我们得让我们的主干网供应商高兴  不管是谁
we'd want to keep our backbone provider happy, whoever they are.
你觉得呢  戈登
What do you think, Gordon?
如果世通想抬价  那可以
If MCI wants more money, fine.
我们有钱  给他们好了
We've got it. Let's give it to them.
不是只有美国在线财力雄厚
AOL's not the only one with deep pockets.
我们要保持优势
Let's stay ahead of this.
谢普  去打电话
Shep, get a call in.
乔  谢谢你今天来
And, uh, Joe, thanks for sitting in today.
这是什么
What is this?
北极星
Loadstar.
是完成的浏览器吗
Is that the finished browser?
你就一直拖着
You've just been sitting on this?
没时间早点交过来吗
Couldn't get around to handing it in?
不是  我昨晚完成的
No. I finished it last night.
怎么  一天就做好了
So, it was, what, a day of work?
乔  我研究这个好几周了
Joe, I've been working on this for weeks.
你并不需要干坐着等我的
You know, you didn't have to sit around and wait for me.
你要是那么急
If you were in such a rush,
你另雇个人写代码就好了
you could have hired somebody else to do the coding.
你不懂  我需要你的
You don't get it. I needed you.
我们需要你在乎  可你不在乎
We needed you to care, and you didn't.
我们原本比马赛克的人早开始近一年
We had almost a year on the Mosaic guys,
但我们错过了机会  现在
but we blew it, and now...
要是你在  真在这儿工作
If you had just been here, actually been available...
我不能来这儿  情况就是这样
Well, I couldn't be here. That was the deal.
那对我很不公平
And it was a raw deal for me.
而且太遗憾了
And it's just a shame.
很遗憾五千英里还是不够远
It's a shame that 5,000 miles away wasn't far enough.
你究竟在气什么
What is this about?
我已经把这个做得比需要的好很多了
Look, I made this better than it had any right to be,
而且我同时还得处理好多我自己的事
and I did so while dealing with a lot of my own stuff.
是啊  你的游戏
Oh, right, your game.
我相信你肯定很不容易
I'm sure that was tough,
有资金  受提拔  受宠爱
being funded, promoted, coddled.
我一直一个人
I've been alone on this,
在这上研究了三年
working by myself for three years.
你想谈谈我们真正在谈的事吗
Do you want to talk about what we're really talking about?
如果我们做这个了
If we had worked on this...
一起做
together...
本可以非常了不起的
it could have been amazing.
你想要我做什么
What do you want me to do?
什么都不用
Nothing.
太迟了
It's too late.
而且  我得继续工作了  那就...
And I, um, got to get back to work, so...
看现在的情况
You know, the way things are growing...
你很快就要没便贴可用了
you're gonna run out of Post-its pretty soon.
告诉俄勒冈州  他们市场不够大
Well, tell Oregon they're not a big enough market
不吸引数字用户投资
for Digital Subscriber investments.
我们开始吧
Let's get started.
首先  容我说
Well, first off, let me just say,
仅代表流浪者智囊团
on behalf of the Rover brain trust,
很高兴再次见到你
it's great to see you again.
我们已结束了测试阶段
We're moving past the beta phase.
我们已在三个医学院起步
We are already underway in three med schools,
还有两家也提出了请求
with requests for two more.
但不那么可喜的是
A little more sobering, though,
我们比预期稍快了一点
is that we've gone through our seed round
耗尽了我们的种子基金  现在
just a hair faster than expected, and now...
现在你们需要更多钱
Now you need more money.
是的
Well, yes.
要么就得裁员
It's either that or we let some people go...
主要是实习生
interns, mostly.
但这仍是企业软件
But this is still enterprise software,
企业对企业  目前只针对医疗记录
B2B currently focused only on medical records.
是的  用二进制查询进入数据库
Yes, through binary queries into the data pool,
但我们在进行改善  以期实现更多同类应用
but we're refining comparisons to make things more versatile.
好吧  我直说了
Okay, I'll just cut to the chase here.
我给你们的资金够你们做医疗数据库项目了
I've given you enough funding for a medical database program.
如果你们想要更多资金  我需要更大的点子
If you want more funding, I will need a bigger idea.
24小时后我们再谈吧
Let's talk again in 24 hours.
这也太快了吧
Uh, that's a mighty quick turnaround.
是啊
Yes. Yes, it is.
戈登
Gordon.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
怎么了
What's up?
我有想法
I've got something.
我们还可以做那扇门
We can still be the door.
或许不是个浏览器  事实上  不该是
Maybe it's not a browser. In fact, it shouldn't be.
我们要建个网站  任何浏览器都可以登录
We're gonna build a website that is accessible from any browser.
就像一个网站的网站
Like a... Like a website of websites,
一个收录一切的索引  名录
an index of everything, like a directory.
怎么  像黄页吗
What, like the Yellow Pages?
对  但不止如此
Yes, but more than that.
我还没想透彻  但是
I don't have the full thing yet, but...
乔
Look, Joe.
乔  你先打住吧
Joe, let me stop you right there.
我以为你回来做正事了
I thought you were back on the business,
我们的正事  这个生意
our business, this business.
你什么时候才能醒过来啊
When are you gonna wake up?
-什么  -你在梦游
- What? - You're sleepwalking.
那个派对算什么  戈登
I mean, what the hell was that party, Gordon?
我想庆祝我们的成功
I wanted to celebrate our success.
你是想说服自己
You're trying to convince yourself
你可以停下  虽然你的一切直觉
that it's okay to stop when every fiber of your being
都在让你继续
is telling yourself to keep going.
我这么多年一直跟你说  你是个建造者
I've been telling you for years that you are a builder.
你得建造
You need to build.
知道吗  乔  我建造了这个
You know what, Joe? I built this.
我建造了这一切  而你在楼下的地下室里
I built all of this when you were downstairs in the basement
玩便贴
screwing around with Post-it notes.
是卡梅伦让你说这些的吗
Did Cameron put you up to this?
我看到她今天来过了
I noticed that she stopped by today.
当然是她
Of course she did.
听着  我们只是希望你
Look, all we're asking is that you
把游戏操作写入手册
put the game's controls in the manual.
-不行  -就是这样
- No. - That's it.
不  对于魔术  最糟的
No, the worst thing you can do with a magic trick
就是解释其原理
is explain how it works.
不管观众如何要求
No matter how much the audience asks,
让他们自己去发现
it's so much more rewarding
效果会好得多
if they get to discover it for themselves.
你得尊重玩家
You have to respect the player.
怎么样
So?
是个精彩的旅程吧
It's a trip, huh?
卡梅伦  你来这儿干什么
Cameron, what are you doing here?
我说了  我得推广游戏
I told you. I have to promote the game.
不  我是问你究竟来干吗
No, I mean, what are you doing here?
这些破事本来都放下了
This shit was all behind us.
浏览器吗
The browser?
乔
Joe.
你根本不知道  他花了多大力气
You have no idea how hard he's worked
才回到他现在的状态  我又付出了多少
to get back to where he is... how hard I've worked.
现在  突然
And now, all of a sudden, you know,
你对没拿出北极星感到歉疚
you feel guilty about no-showing on Loadstar.
你回到了他的生活中  让他又开始发狂了
You come back into his life and you got him spinning.
-我什么都没做  -你跟他在地下室
- I didn't do anything. - Look, you spent five minutes with him
谈了五分钟  现在他就坚信
in the basement, and now he's convinced
你从山顶取了圣火给他
that you've handed him fire from the mountaintop.
我不是说你是有意的
Look, I'm not saying that you're doing this on purpose,
但每次你回到他的生活中
but every single time that you come back into his life...
那东西是我欠他的
I owed him that work.
欠你们俩的
I owed both of you.
昨天  你问我  你是不是残忍
You know, yesterday you asked me if you were cruel.
抱歉  这个房间我们只能用到10点
Sorry. We only have the room until 10:00.
见到你很高兴  戈登
It was great to see you, Gordon.
是啊  上帝为何要创造宿醉
Yeah. I mean, isn't that why God created hangovers...
不就是为了教青少年别喝那么多吗
teach teenagers not to drink so much?
不单是喝酒的事
Drinking is one thing.
至少在家里喝  有家长看着
Okay, well, it's better off at home with one of us
总好过在外面喝  是吧
than somewhere else, right?
戈登  没事的
Gordon, it's fine.
她跟你说她不去大学了吗
She told you she's not going to college yet,
还是这话依然只是用来折磨我的
or is she still just torturing me with that one?
我们的女儿思想这么自由也是好事
It's a positive that our daughter has such a free spirit.
琼妮绝对是够机灵
Well, Joanie is certainly resourceful.
你不会相信她都用了多少家居用品
You wouldn't believe the variety of household items...
甚至用水果
fruit, even...
来抽大麻
she's found a way to smoke pot out of.
这就是个卖点了
Well, there's your selling point right there.
她会喜欢伯克利的
She'd love Berkeley.
我会跟她谈的
I'll talk to her.
谢谢
Thank you.
前两天看到卡梅伦感觉好怪
It was weird to see Cameron the other day,
还穿着你的运动裤
especially in your sweatpants.
你知道的
Oh, well, you know,
她一直超级喜欢我的
she's always had a major, major thing for me.
才不会
No.
我喜欢你觉得
Yeah, well, I liked that you thought
还有这种可能性
it was even a possibility.
你知道关于马赛克她对我说了什么吗
You know what she said to me about Mosaic?
她说  "我很意外居然不是你的"
She said, "I was surprised it wasn't you."
那是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
我不知道
I don't know.
她最近的来访让乔对一个新点子
Her latest visit's got Joe jumping up and down
-激动得上蹿下跳  -当然了
- about some new idea. - Of course.
他突然觉得
Yeah, I mean, he suddenly thinks
他该为所有现存的网站做个索引
he should index every website in existence.
那要怎么做到啊
How would you even do that?
相信我  他这三年来一直在一丝不苟地
Trust me, he's been meticulously building a list of URLs...
徒手建立一个网址清单
by hand... for the last three years.
听上去好乏味啊
That sounds awfully tedious.
是啊
Yeah, well, you know.
乔嘛  咬住不放的人
Joe... dog with a bone.
是啊
That he is.
而卡梅伦喜欢喷彩虹出来
And Cameron loves to shit out rainbows
好让人不去在意她的混蛋行为
to distract from her asshole behavior.
我想要鲑鱼  你呢
I'm gonna do the salmon. You?
不错  我也要一样的吧
Sounds good. I'll do the same.
敬马赛克
Here's to Mosaic...
以及我们各自对手浏览器的死亡
and the respective death of our competing browsers.
好消息  我们做到了
Good news. We nailed it.
杂志
Magazines.
我们用算法做大型出版物
We use the algorithm to index back catalogs
历史目录的索引  一本本地做
of major publications one magazine at a time.
好了  这些文本文件
Voilà... a trove of text documents
有一个非结构化数据问题
with an unstructured data problem
正等着人来解决
just waiting to be solved.
不  那个不行
No, that's not it.
我们还讨论了法律服务
We also discussed legal service...
案件和先例的历史档案
backlogs of briefs and precedents.
-我们...  -这些都是积压数据
- Well, we... - Look, this is all dead data.
什么在增长
What's growing?
我们能把算法用在什么有活力的东西上
What can we apply the algorithm to that's dynamic?
我们做的是未来的生意
We're in the future business here.
我不知道要怎么为实时数据做索引
I don't know how we index live data.
那太不幸了
Ah, well, then that's unfortunate.
网络呢
Uh, well, what about the Web?
光是这一年  网站数量就增长了500%
The... The number of websites has grown 500% this year alone.
到了明年  就可能呈指数增长
By next year, it could grow exponentially.
到时  数据库从理论上讲是无限的
At that point, the data pool's theoretically limitless.
我们得调整算法
We'd have to adjust the algorithm,
但我们可以尝试为整个网络做索引
but we could endeavor to index the entire Web,
好供人搜索
make it searchable.
要怎么做索引呢
And how would you index it?
用算法
W-With the algorithm.
要完全自动化  计算机化
It'd be fully automated and computerized.
那么就要几乎能做到即时更新
That means it'd be up to date almost instantly
每一个新增的网站
with every new site addition.
就是这个
That's it.
就是这个点子
That's the idea.
别告诉我破解恩索谜题的奖励
Don't tell me the reward for solving Enso puzzle
就是被传送回游戏开始
was getting transported back to the beginning of the game.
我恐怕有坏消息要告诉你
I'm afraid I've got some bad news for you.
那么恩索是个零  我得重新开始
So the Enso is a zero, and I've got to start over.
或许  它是一切
Or maybe it means everything.
现在你可以以全新的方式
Now you can approach the path you've taken
走上你走过的道路了
in an entirely new way.
那天的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about the other day.
我就是不愿相信
I was just having trouble believing that
浏览器已经结束了
the browser was done,
我知道  那个
and I know that that is...
已经结束了
over now.
真的
I do.
不管怎样  我不希望要
Regardless, I don't want five months
过五个月或五年才能再跟你联系
or five years to go by before I hear from you.
别再消失了
So don't disappear again.
我希望你能  常在我生活中
I want to... know you in my life.
你已经很了解我了  乔
You already know me, Joe.
我不回日本了
I'm not going back to Japan.
汤姆离开了我
Tom left me.